A Finding Aid to the American Federation of Arts Records, 1895-1993 (bulk 1909-1969), in the Archives of American Art AAA.amerfeda
Archives of American Art
- Administrative Records, 1910-1966; Series 2; (boxes 4-8)
  - Alphabetical Files, 1910-1966; 2.1
    - Dealers' Advisory Committee Project, 1960 (Box 5)
    - De Young Museum, San Francisco, 1966 (Box 5)
    - F, General, 1953-1965 (Box 5)
    - 50th Anniversary, 1959 (Box 5)
      - Award Citations, 1959 (Box 5)
      - Awards, 1959 (Box 5)
      - Casebook, 1959 (Box 5)
      - Casebook Statements from Small Museum Directors, 1957-1959 (Box 5)
      - Committee Acceptances, 1959 (Box 5)
      - Philadelphia Reception, 1959 (Box 5)
      - Utica Celebration, 1959 (Box 5)
    - Film Festival, 1957, 1963 (Box 5)
    - Films on Art, 1952-1956 (Box 5)
    - Fund for the Republic, 1956 (Box 5)
    - Glick & Lorwin, Inc., First and Second Annual Displays of Free and Inexpensive Teaching Aids, 1955-1956 (Box 5)
    - Government and Art, Committee on, 1950-1962 (Box 5)
    - Edith Gregor Halpert Foundation (Box 6)
      - Award for Critical Writing, 1952-1955, 1965, undated (Box 6)
      - Correspondence, General, 1951-1960 (Box 6)
      - Survey of Contemporary American Art, 1953-1955 (Box 6)
    - Holmes Report, 1956-1958 (Box 6)
    - Institute of International Education, 1954-1958 (Box 6)
    - International Art Exchange Program, 1958-1960 (Box 6)
    - Job Applications, 1952-1960 (Box 6)
    - Joint Artists-Museums Committee, 1955-1957 (Box 6)
    - Joint Committee on Educational Television, 1951-1953 (Box 6)
    - Joint Committee on the National Capital, 1955-1961 (Box 6)
    - K-L, General, 1957-1961 (Box 6)
    - Latin American Project, 1958 (Box 6)
    - Life, New Reproduction Process, 1956 (Box 6)
    - Lilly Endowment, Inc., 1953-1954 (Box 6)
    - Los Angeles County Art Museum, Director's Resignation, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Magazine of Art, 1949-1953 (Box 6)
    - M, General, 1954-1962 (Box 6)
    - Membership and Development, 1952-1962 (Box 6)
    - Morley, Grace L. McCann, 1951-1962 (Box 6)
    - Moscow Show, 1959 (Box 6)
    - National Sculpture Society, 1952 (Box 6)
    - P, General, 1952-1958 (Box 6)
    - Peck and Peck, 1953 (Box 6)
    - Personnel (including director search), 1955-1956 (Box 6)
    - Public Relations, 1957-1961 (Box 6)
    - Publications (AFA), 1939-1966, undated (Box 6)
    - Publicity, A and B Lists, 1960-1961 (Box 6)
    - Publicity, Clippings, 1950-1966 (Box 6)
    - Publicity, Correspondence, 1955-1960 (Box 7)
    - Publicity, Magazine Article "Art in Your Life,", undated (Box 7)
    - Publicity, Photographs, 1954-1955, undated (Box 7)
    - Publicity, Press Releases, 1953-1958, undated (Box 7)
    - Publicity, Special, 1953 (Box 7)
    - Publicity, Trustee Officers and Staff, 1956-1963 (Box 7)
    - R, General, 1954-1959 (Box 7)
    - Refregier Murals, 1953 (Box 7)
    - Ruder and Finn, 1953-1956, undated (Box 7)
    - S, General, 1957-1961 (Box 7)
    - Show Magazine Opening, 1962 (Box 7)
    - State Sponsored Art Programs, Survey and Analysis, 1962-1963 (Box 7)
    - State Sponsored Art Programs, Correspondence, 1962-1963, 1965-1968 (Box 7)
    - State Sponsored Art Programs, State Councils on the Arts, 1964-1967 (Box 7)
    - Statement of Director before Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare to Fine Arts Bills, 1962 (Box 7)
    - T, General, 1959-1963 (Box 7)
    - Trustees, Files on Individuals (Box 7)
      - Allerton, John Gregg, 1965 (Box 7)
      - Avnet, Lester, 1964-1969 (Box 7)
      - Barr, Alfred H., Jr., 1952-1956 (Box 7)
      - Belluschi, Pietro, 1954 (Box 7)
      - Berkowitz, Sidney, 1952-1957 (Box 7)
      - Blair, William McCormick, 1961-1964 (Box 7)
      - Bliss, Robert Woods, 1951-1962 (Box 7)
      - Bonner, Paul Hyde, 1953-1954 (Box 7)
      - Colin, Ralph F., 1952-1956 (Box 7)
      - Cowles, Russell, 1951-1953 (Box 7)
      - Crosby, Sumner McK., 1951-1954 (Box 7)
      - Defenbacher, Daniel S., 1951-1954 (Box 7)
      - de Menil, John, 1958-1965 (Box 7)
      - Fuller, Adelaide P., 1964-1966 (Box 7)
      - Graves, Katharine I., 1961-1963 (Box 7)
      - Hanna, Leonard, 1954-1958 (Box 7)
      - d'Harnoncourt, René, 1951-1958 (Box 7)
      - Haswell, Anthony, 1955 (Box 7)
      - Hayes, Bartlett H., Jr., 1951-1964 (Box 7)
      - Hope, Henry R., 1951-1960 (Box 7)
      - Houghton, Arthur A., 1952-1956 (Box 7)
      - Iselin, Lewis, 1966 (Box 7)
      - Jarvis, Alan, 1960-1965 (Box 7)
      - List, Vera G. (Mrs. Albert A.), 1959-1968 (Box 7)
      - Longwell, Daniel, 1952-1954; 1956--1961 (Box 7)
      - Ludgin, Earle, 1950-1954 (Box 7)
      - Marcus, Stanley, 1952-1967 (Box 7)
      - Maremont, Adele and Arnold, 1958-1968 (Box 7)
      - Miller, Elizabeth F. (Mrs. Robert Watt), 1960-1964 (Box 7)
      - Murray, William C., 1957-1964 (Box 7)
      - Nagel, Charles, Jr., 1954-1966 (Box 7)
      - Olsen, Fred, 1958 (Box 7)
      - Palmer, Fred L., 1955-1959 (Box 7)
      - Pei, I. M., 1964-1966 (Box 7)
      - Rentschler, Rita (Mrs. George A.), 1959-1961 (Box 7)
      - Rudd, Thomas Brown, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
      - Russell, Helen G. (Mrs. Henry P.), 1954-1966 (Box 7)
      - Saltonstall, Nathaniel, 1965 (Box 7)
      - Sawyer, Charles H., 1951-1956 (Box 7)
      - Schenck, Edgar C., 1959, undated (Box 7)
      - Slocum, John J., 1964 (Box 7)
      - Smythe, Craig, 1954 (Box 7)
      - Soby, James Thrall, 1950-1956 (Box 7)
      - Stone, Edward D., 1960 (Box 7)
      - Taylor, Francis Henry, 1951-1957 (Box 7)
      - Tremaine, Emily Hall (Mrs. Burton G., Jr.), 1951-1953 (Box 7)
      - Wintersteen, Bernice McIlhenny (Mrs. John), 1966 (Box 7)
    - Zurcher, Suzette M., 1952-1962 (Box 7)
    - Trustees, Memoranda to, 1951-1953 (Box 7)
    - Trustees, Nominations, 1954-1960 (Box 7)
    - Trustees, Photographs, undated (Box 7)
    - UNESCO, 1958-1961 (Box 7)
    - U.S. Government Officials, 1959-1961 (Box 7)
    - USIA-AFA Relations, Press Reactions, 1954-1956 (Box 7)
    - W, General, 1953-1962 (Box 7)
    - Woodstock Art Conference, "The Artist and the Museum,", 1950 (Box 7)
  - Staff Records, 1927-1966; 2.2
    - Director Alexander B. Trowbridge, Correspondence, 1927-1928 (Box 8)
    - Acting Director Andrew Wright Crawford, Correspondence, 1929 (Box 8)
    - Director Harris K. Prior, Correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 8)
    - Director Roy Moyer, Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 8)
    - Assistant Director Robert H. Luck, Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 8)
    - Special Representative Robert H. Luck, Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 8)
    - Registrar (Box 8)
      - Insurance Claims, 1947-1962 (Box 8)
      - Insurance, General, 1955-1963 (Box 8)
      - Customs, 1960-1962 (Box 8)
      - Sales, 1958-1960 (Box 8)
      - Shipping, 1962-1963 (Box 8)
    - General Correspondence, 1963 (Box 8)
- Special Programs, 1950-1967; Series 3; (boxes 9-13)
  This series is organized into 6 subseries.
  3.1: Artists in Residence (Ford Foundation), 1957-1966
  3.2: Ford Foundation Program for Visual Artists
  3.3: Museum Donor Program, 1959-1967
  3.4: New York State Council on the Arts Circulating Exhibitions Program, 1959-1966
  3.5: Picture of the Month, 1951-1958
  3.6: Jean Tennyson Foundation Color Slide Lecture Program, 1950-1962 and undated
  - Artists in Residence (Ford Foundation), 1957-1966; 3.1
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 9)
    - Future Possibilities, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
    - Replies Pending, A-Z, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
    - Refusals, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
    - Unsolicited, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
    - Artists in Residence (Box 9)
      - Abramowitz, Benjamin, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
      - Adler, Samuel, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
      - Alps, Glen, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
      - Apple, Billy, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
      - Azuma, Norio, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
      - Barnet, Will, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Blanch, Arnold, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Blaustein, Alfred, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
      - Brach, Paul, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
      - Brackman, Robert, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
      - Browning, Colleen, 1957, undated (Box 9)
      - Burford, Byron, 1964-1966 (Box 9)
      - Calcagno, Lawrence, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
      - Callahan, Kenneth, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
      - Chapin, Francis, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Chieffo, Clifford T., 1963-1966 (Box 9)
      - Citron, Minna, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
      - Cohen, George, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
      - Cox, Jan, 1963 (Box 9)
      - Crawford, Ralston, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
      - Davis, Jerrold, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Decker, Lindsey, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
      - De Diego, Julio, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Delap, Tony, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
      - Dienes, Sari, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
      - Drexler, Sherman, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Dugmore, Edward, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
      - Ernst, Jimmy, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
      - Florsheim, Richard, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Fogel, Seymour, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Forst, Miles, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
      - Freimark, Robert, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
      - Giobbi, Edward, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
      - Gonzalez, Xavier, 1964-1966 (Box 9)
      - Gray, Cleve, 1963 (Box 9)
      - Greene, Stephen, 1965 (Box 9)
      - Grillo, John, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Gropper, William, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
      - Hare, David, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Henselmann, Caspar, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
      - Hultberg, John, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
      - Ippolito, Angelo, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
      - Kanemitsu, Matsumi (Mike), 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Kantor, Morris, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
      - Koerner, Henry, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Lahey, Richard, 1965 (Box 9)
      - Mallary, Robert, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
      - Marcus, Marcia, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
      - Margo, Boris, 1959-1965 (Box 9)
      - Martinelli, Exio, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Martin, Fletcher, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Massin, Eugene, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
      - McGarrelll, James, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Millman, Edward, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Mitchell, Fred, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
      - Murch, Walter, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Natkin, Robert, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Pachner, William, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Parker, Raymond, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Peterdi, Gabor, 1963-1965 (Box 10)
      - Pickhardt, Carl, 1964-1966 (Box 10)
      - Quirt, Walter, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Reinhardt, Ad, 1964-1966 (Box 10)
      - Rockmore, Noel, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Roth, Frank, 1966 (Box 10)
      - Ruben, Richards, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Saltzman, William, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
      - Schwartz, Aubrey, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Shapiro, Seymour, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
      - Soffer, Sasson, 1964-1966 (Box 10)
      - Sonenberg, Jack, 1063-1966 (Box 10)
      - Stankiewicz, Richard, 1964-1965 (Box 10)
      - Stuempfig, Walter, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Summers, Carol, 1965 (Box 10)
      - Takal, Peter, 1964-1965 (Box 10)
      - Vickrey, Robert R., 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Waldman, Paul, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
      - Wildenhain, Marguerite, 1963-1966 (Box 10)
      - Wilson, Ben, 1965 (Box 10)
      - Wines, James, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Youngerman, Jack, 1964-1966 (Box 10)
      - Yunkers, Adja, 1963-1966 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1967, undated (Box 10)
    - Lists, Artists, 1963-1967 (Box 10)
    - Lists, Works, 1964-1966 (Box 10)
    - Museums (Box 10)
      - Correspondence, General, 1963 (Box 10)
      - Future Possibilities, 1963-1966 (Box 10)
      - Refusals, 1963-1965 (Box 10)
      - Replies Pending, A-Z, 1963-1965 (Box 10)
    - Publicity, undated, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Reports, 1963-1965 (Box 10)
  - Ford Foundation Program for Visual Artists, 3.2
    - Grants-in-Aid Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 10)
    - Purchase Awards, 1959-1960 (Box 10)
      - Correspondence, General, 1959-1960 (Box 10)
      - Insurance Claim, 1960 (Box 10)
      - National Jury, 1959-1960 (Box 10)
    - Retrospective Exhibitions, 1958-1963 (Box 10)
      - Budgets, 1959-1961, undated (Box 10)
      - Catalogs, 1959-1962 (Box 10)
      - Color Transparencies, undated (Box 10)
      - Comments, 1960, undated (Box 10)
      - Correspondence, General, 1958-1963 (Box 10)
      - General Information, 1958-1961 (Box 10)
      - Inquiries and Bookings (arranged by location) (Box 10)
        - Abroad, 1960 (Box 10)
        - Alabama, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
        - Arizona, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
        - Arkansas, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
        - California, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
        - Canada, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
        - Colorado, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
        - Connecticut, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
        - Delaware, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
        - District of Columbia, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
        - Florida, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
        - Georgia, 1959-1962 (Box 10)
        - Hawaii, 1962-1963 (Box 10)
        - Idaho, 1959-1960 (Box 10)
        - Illinois, 1959-1962 (Box 11)
        - Indiana, 1959-1962 (Box 11)
        - Iowa, 1959-1963 (Box 11)
        - Oregon, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
        - Pennsylvania, 1959-1962 (Box 11)
        - Puerto Rico, 1960 (Box 11)
        - Rhode Island, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
        - South Carolina, 1959-1962 (Box 11)
        - South Dakota, 1959-1962 (Box 11)
        - Tennessee, 1959-1963 (Box 11)
        - Texas, 1959-1962 (Box 11)
        - Utah, 1959-1960 (Box 11)
        - Vermont, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
        - Virginia, 1959-1962 (Box 11)
        - Washington, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
        - West Virginia, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
        - Wisconsin, 1959-1962 (Box 11)
        - Wyoming, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
      - Insurance Claims, 1958-1959 (Box 11)
      - Insurance Valuations, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
      - Itineraries, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
      - Jury Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 11)
      - Jury Reports, 1958-1959 (Box 11)
      - Proposals, 1960-1961 (Box 11)
      - Publicity (Box 11)
        - Clippings, 1960-1963, undated (Box 11)
        - Press Releases, 1958-1959 (Box 11)
      - Questionnaire, 1960 (Box 11)
      - Refusals, 1959 (Box 11)
      - Reports, 1960-1964 (Box 11)
  - Museum Donor Program, 1959-1967; 3.3
    - Accepted Applications (Box 11)
      - Achenbach Foundation for Graphic Arts, 1964-1965 (Box 11)
      - Addison Gallery of American Art, Phillips Academy, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
      - Albion College, 1966-1967 (Box 11)
      - Allentown Art Museum, 1966-1967 (Box 11)
      - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1959 (Box 11)
      - Carnegie Institute, Department of Fine Arts, 1961 (Box 11)
      - Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center, 1962 (Box 11)
      - Currier Gallery of Art, 1960 (Box 11)
      - Davenport Municipal Art Gallery, 1963-1964 (Box 11)
      - Dayton Art Institute, 1963-1964 (Box 11)
      - Delgado Museum, 1959 (Box 11)
      - Dennison University, 1966-1967 (Box 11)
      - Denver Art Museum, 1960 (Box 11)
      - Everhart Museum, 1964-1965 (Box 11)
      - Howard University, 1962 (Box 11)
      - McNay Art Institute, 1961 (Box 11)
      - Miles College, 1964-1965 (Box 11)
      - Milwaukee Art Center, 1960 (Box 11)
      - Montclair Art Museum, 1960 (Box 12)
      - Morgan State College, 1962 (Box 12)
      - Museum of African Art, 1964-1965 (Box 12)
      - Oakland Art Museum, 1959 (Box 12)
      - Pasadena Art Museum, 1962 (Box 12)
      - Portland [Maine] Art Museum, 1966-1967 (Box 12)
      - Rochester Memorial Art Gallery, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
      - San Francisco Museum of Art, 1960 (Box 12)
      - Talladega College, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
      - Tougaloo College, 1966-1967 (Box 12)
      - University of California at Los Angeles, 1961 (Box 12)
      - University of Massachusetts, 1964-1965 (Box 12)
      - University of Nebraska, 1961 (Box 12)
      - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1960-1961 (Box 12)
      - Wadsworth Athenaeum (Box 12)
      - White Museum of Art, Cornell University, 1959 (Box 12)
      - Williams College, 1961 (Box 12)
      - Worcester Art Institute, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
    - Applications, Not Granted, 1959-1964 (Box 12)
    - Applications, Proposed Institutions, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Applications, Refused, 1964-1965 (Box 12)
    - Applications, To Be Submitted, 1965-1967 (Box 12)
    - Applications, Unsolicited, 1965 (Box 12)
    - General Correspondence, 1960-1966 (Box 12)
    - Currier, Audrey B. and Stephen R., 1966-1967 (Box 12)
    - Selection of Works, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
    - Special Project, Nell Blaine, 1965-1966 (Box 12)
      - Summary, 1959-1967 (Box 12)
  - New York State Council on the Arts Circulating Exhibitions Program, 1959-1966; 3.4
    - Budgets and Expenditures, 1961-1962 (Box 12)
    - Comments from Exhibitors, 1962-1963 (Box 12)
    - Condition Reports, 1962-1963 (Box 12)
    - Exhibition Proposals, 1962-1963, undated (Box 12)
    - Exhibition Files (Box 12)
      - John Francis Cropsey (tentative), 1964 (Box 12)
      - Portrait of Jefferson (dropped), 1964 (Box 12)
      - The River: Places and People, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
    - Inquiries and Bookings (arranged by location) (Box 12)
      - Akron, N.Y., 1961-1962 (Box 12)
      - Albany, N.Y., 1961-1962 (Box 12)
      - Albertson, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Alfred, N.Y., 1961 (Box 12)
      - Armonk, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Auburn, N.Y., 1961 (Box 12)
      - Batavia, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Binghamton, N.Y., 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - Brockport, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Bronxville, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Brooklyn, N.Y., 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - Buffalo, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Canton, N.Y., 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - Cazenovia, N.Y., 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - Chautauqua, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Cincinnatus, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Clinton, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Corning, N.Y., 1961-1962 (Box 12)
      - Cortland, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Eastchester, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Elmira, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Farmingdale, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Floral Park, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Flushing, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Fort Edward, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Fredonia, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Garden City, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Geneseo, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Glens Falls, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Hempstead, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Highland Falls, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Hornell, N.Y., 1961 (Box 12)
      - Houghton, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Ithaca, N.Y., 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - Jamaica, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Jamestown, N.Y., 1961 (Box 12)
      - Katonah, N.Y., 1961 (Box 12)
      - Kinderhook, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Kingston, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Loudenville, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Lynbrook, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Massena, N.Y., 1961-1962 (Box 12)
      - Middletown, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Newberg, N.Y., 1961 (Box 12)
      - New Paltz, N.Y., 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - New York, N.Y., 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - Northport, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Ogdensberg, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Oneonta, N.Y., 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - Oswego, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Plattsburgh, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Port Washington, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Potsdam, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Poughkeepsie, N.Y., 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - Purchase, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Rochester, N.Y., 1961-1962 (Box 12)
      - Rockville Centre, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Rome, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Rye, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Scarsdale, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Schenectady, N.Y., 1961-1962 (Box 12)
      - Setauket, N.Y., 1962-1964 (Box 12)
      - Southampton, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Staten Island, N.Y., 1961-1962 (Box 12)
      - Syracuse, N.Y., 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - Tarrytown, N.Y., 1961-1962 (Box 12)
      - Troy, N.Y., 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - Utica, N.Y., 1961-1962 (Box 12)
      - Wantagh, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Warsaw, N.Y., 1963 (Box 12)
      - Warwick, N.Y., 1961 (Box 12)
      - Watertown, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Wellsville, N.Y., 1961-1962 (Box 12)
      - White Plains, N.Y., 1962 (Box 12)
      - Yonkers, N.Y., 1962-1963 (Box 12)
      - Out of State, 1961-1963 (Box 12)
    - Itineraries, 1961-1963 (Box 13)
    - Lists, New York State Historical Societies, 1963 (Box 13)
    - Lists, Nonprofit Institutions in New York State, 1959-1961 (Box 13)
    - Loans, Temporary, 1963 (Box 13)
    - Loans, Temporary to New York City Offices, 1964 (Box 13)
    - Plans, 1963-1964 (Box 13)
    - Programs, 1962-1966, undated (Box 13)
    - Publicity, 1962-1963 (Box 13)
    - Reports, 1961-1963 (Box 13)
    - Rockefeller, Gov. Nelson A., 1962 (Box 13)
  - Picture of the Month, 1951-1958; 3.5
    - Applications and Agreements for Exhibition Display, 1954-1955 (Box 13)
    - Billing, 1954-1955 (Box 13)
    - Borrowers, 1954-1956 (Box 13)
    - Budget and Administration, 1953-1955 (Box 13)
    - Condition Reports, 1951-1952 (Box 13)
    - Condition Reports and Related Correspondence, 1955-1958 (Box 13)
    - Desirable Paintings, undated (Box 13)
    - Dispersals of Loans, 1955-1956 (Box 13)
    - Documentation Research Source Sheets, 1956-1957, undated (Box 13)
    - Inquiries, 1954-1956 (Box 13)
    - Lenders, 1956-1958 (Box 13)
    - Photographs and Negatives, 1955-1958, undated (Box 13)
    - Promotion, 1955 (Box 13)
    - Publicity, 1950s (Box 13)
    - Report to Chairman of the Exhibition Committee, 1954 (Box 13)
    - Questionnaires, 1953-1954 (Box 13)
    - Shippings, 1955 (Box 13)
  - Jean Tennyson Foundation Color Slide Lecture Program, 1950-1962; undated; 3.6
    - Bills and Expenses, 1954 (Box 13)
    - Contracts, 1954-1956 (Box 13)
    - Copyright, 1952-1954 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, Bookings, 1954-1962 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, Daily File, 1954 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 13)
    - Tennyson Foundation, 1952-1954 (Box 13)
    - Dispersal, 1960-1963 (Box 13)
    - General Information, 1952 (Box 13)
    - Lecture Texts and Slide Lists, undated (Box 13)
    - Publicity, undated (Box 13)
    - Slides, undated (Box 13)
    - Questionnaires, 1952 (Box 13)
- Annual Conventions, 1912-1963; Series 4; (boxes 14-16)
  - 3rd Annual Convention Program, 1912 (Box 14)
  - 5th Annual Convention Proceedings, 1914 (Box 14)
  - 7th Annual Convention Proceedings, 1916 (Box 14)
  - 8th Annual Convention Proceedings, 1917 (Box 14)
  - 10th Annual Convention Proceedings, 1919 (Box 14)
  - 12th Annual Convention, 1921 (Box 14)
    - Proceedings (Box 14)
    - Resolutions (Box 14)
    - Speeches (Box 14)
  - 15th Annual Convention Proceedings, 1924 (Box 14)
  - 18th Annual Convention Proceedings, 1927 (Box 14)
  - 19th Annual Convention, 1928 (Box 14)
    - Proceedings (Box 14)
    - Speeches (Box 14)
    - 11th Annual Convention, 1920 (Box 14)
      - Plans, 1919-1920 (Box 14)
      - Proceedings (Box 14)
  - 20th Annual Convention Proceedings, 1929 (Box 14)
  - 21st Annual Convention Proceedings, 1930 (Box 14)
  - 23rd Annual Convention Proceedings, 1932 (Box 14)
  - 24th Annual Convention Addresses, 1933 (Box 14)
  - 25th Annual Convention Proceedings, 1934 (Box 15)
  - 26th Annual Convention Proceedings, 1935 (Box 15)
  - 41st Annual Convention Notes, 1950 (Box 15)
  - 42nd Annual Convention, 1951 (Box 15)
    - Program (Box 15)
    - Sound Recordings of Proceedings (on twelve 7 ½ inch reel-to-reel tapes) (Box 15)
  - 44th Convention, 1953 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence of Director Burton Cummings (Box 15)
    - Photographs (Box 15)
  - 45th Annual Convention, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Program (Box 15)
    - Correspondence of Burton Cummings (Box 15)
    - Texts of Speeches (Box 15)
  - 46th Annual Convention, 1955 (Box 15)
    - Convention Committee Correspondence (Box 15)
    - Photographs and Clippings (Box 15)
    - Speeches (Box 15)
  - 48th Annual Convention, 1957 (Box 15)
    - Committee Chairman's (Preston M. Bolton) Records, 1956-1957 (Box 15)
    - Exhibitions (Box 15)
    - Photographs and Negatives (Box 15)
    - Publicity (Box 15)
    - Clippings (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, Plans, and Reports (Box 15)
    - Program (Box 15)
    - Press Releases (Box 15)
    - Speakers (Box 15)
    - Speeches, includes panel discussion, "The Creative Act" (Box 15)